

Telephone: (+41) 0762122161

Email:

josejoaquinvillamor@gmail.com

Click the following links to access them:

LinkedIn

Git Hub

Portfolio

Languages



C2



A2

Tools

Excel / Python

90%

SQL / Alteryx

80%

Tableau / Power BI / VBA

65%

Minitab / R / Git

50%

Skills

Data engineering / Automation

ML modeling / NLP techniques

80%

Dashboarding / DB management

65%

Software Engineering

50%

Hobbies











About me

A curious, proactive and eager individual, I have reoriented my career towards data related roles, with experience in data engineering, artificial intelligence, dashboards and databases.

Click the link below to navigate to my portfolio where I have developed several Al base web apps:

Access Portfolio

Experience

• Data Engineer - World Trade Organization (Geneve) 04/10/2021 - Nowadays

Tools used: Python, SQL, Excel, Internal tools

Duties: Process trade data received by menbers and integrate it into the database system. Prepare datasets for analysis and academic research. Support collagues with advanced data wrangling cases.

Achievements: Created a semi-automated workflow to process trade data. Prepare data for a report in Trade of Medial goods carried out by the WTO, IMF and World Bank. Technical supporter of NLP analysis and techniques for a colleague PhD's in subsidies.

• Data Scientist - PwC Malta (Malta) 01/01/2021 - 01/10/2021

Tools used: Python, VBA, JavaScript, SQL, Power BI, Excel, Alteryx

Duties: Development of automation tools and processes using Python, VBA and Alteryx. Implementation of ETL processes, gathering of insights and preparation of dashboards. Identification of ML applications across the firm.

Achievements: Developed phase 2 of the VAT automation tool using VBA and Alteryx. Corrected and expanded features of several scrapping tools.

<u>Data Analyst - Transcom (Leon)</u> 01/11/2018 - 01/01/2021

Tool used: SQL, Excel, PowerPoint, Python, Tableau, BigML, Minitab

Duties: Improve the performance of the services provided and the effectiveness of operations by preparing KPI reports, Machine Learning models and advance analytical techniques

Achievements: Develop a series of ML models to identify best agents in interviews, probability of customer accepting an offer, and cancelling portability among others.

From May 2015 to June 2017 I worked as a Finance consultant managing clients accounts and supporting the audit team before reorienting my carrer to data related roles.

Education

MBA International business - Spanish Chamber of Commerce 01/10/2017 - 07/09/2018

Main Fields of Studies: International markets, logistics, strategy, payments, law and directive skills.

Degree in Finance and Accounting - UC3M (Madrid) 01/10/2010 - 01/06/2014

Main Fields of Studies: Financial markets, instruments, accounting principles, audit, corporate finance and commercial law.

Certifications

Machine Learning - Stanford University (Coursera)

Data Warehousing for BI - University of Colorado (Coursera)

Deep Learning Specialization - DeepLearningAI (Coursera)

Statistics with R Specialization - Duke University (Coursera)

To check all certifications please click the following link: Access all certifications